Kingsley Ukeje, Product Design

+2347031356201, kingsleyukejex@gmail.com

LINKS

Website/Portfolio, LinkedIn, Twitter, Instagram

PROFILE

I have worked internationally, in-house, and remotely on projects for leading brands, agencies, startups, and charities. I care deeply about creating world-class, useful, and beautiful products that help people and make a difference.

I work with different members of the cross-functional product development teams to drive products forward. As a designer or product lead, I like to be involved at different stages of a digital project, from the seed of the idea, through to sketches, design, and even the front-end and back-end build, this means I can jump in at any stage of a project, or take on the whole project, from design to build and ultimately production.

In my professional career, I have had the rare and privileged experience to learn firsthand and be part of building a startup and be part of its growth process to become a multinational brand. My wealth of experience over the past years has enabled me to have a better understanding of what it takes to design, build, deploy and manage digital products.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Feb 2022 — Present

Senior Product Designer, Scalio

San Francisco, USA

Scalio is a global digital product agency headquartered in San Francisco. We design, build and scale high-usability, high-performance custom software for mobile, web, AR, wearable, connected devices, & emerging technologies. At Scalio, I

- Lead client projects from a design perspective
- Design new products and redesign existing ones for Mobile and Web (B2B, B2C, growing startups, healthcare, investment, booking, social networking and education). Apply design thinking processes to advocate for end-users needs and solve business problems.
- Improve the work process and promote design thinking within cross-platform teams.
- Develop creative programs and design concepts that meet the business objectives of the organization and that advance our brand and proposition strategy
- Work with internal teams to generate ideas for pitching and proposals
- Work with other team members to deliver projects and activities to deliver against deadlines

Jun 2021 — Feb 2022

Head of Design, Enyata

Lagos, Nigeria

Enyata is a software development, consultancy, and training company. We focus on equipping people and enabling businesses by providing human-centered software solutions.

I lead a team of 5 made up of visual, product and, user experience designers. I,

- Take responsibility for the creative vision and the standard of output across team members who work under them.
- Pitch ideas conf idently and present the creative vision clearly to clients, as well as communicate in the same manner to members of the creative team.
- Have strong people management and leadership skills in order to hire, develop, and inspire the creative team.
- Ensure that all of the organization's or client's creative output/visuals are consistent with the overall brand.
- Provide creative output and direction to ensure the overall vision for the product is achieved;
- Lead, recruit, coach, and mentor a team of world-class product designers and user researchers;
- Collaborate with members of cross-functional teams and be a champion for user-centered culture and design practices;
- Create visually engaging, innovative, and functional digital products;
- Encourage cross-functional collaboration and communicate the impact of this practice for design;
- Work closely with product managers, engineers, QA, and their leaders to ensure a cohesive user experience across all products;
- Organize teams that can provide design solutions effectively and with excellence across all departments;

- Establish metrics and measurable goals to ensure visibility into design's impact on business;
- Advocate the importance of User-Centered Design and mentoring designers on the design process and deliverable;
- Drive a framework to ensure career progression and development paths for world-class design talents;
- Build design culture that encourages innovation while balancing the need for optimization;
- Communicate the value of design thinking and a customer-first approach to strategy across all areas of the business;
- Partner closely with leaders in engineering, product, sales, marketing, and others to constantly improve on communication and efficiency practices.

Jun 2019 — Jun 2021

Lead, Product Design, Enyata

Lagos, Nigeria

Enyata is a software development, consultancy, and training company.

We focus on equipping people and enabling businesses by providing human-centered software solutions.

I lead a team of 4 designers:

- Influencing design-led thinking across the business
- Responsible for developing and managing all aspects of our design and creative output. Lead concept development in relation to design and creative outputs
- Lead with accountability for online and offline design output and commercial success of the design and creative department.
- Ensure design and creative deliverables are aligned to client expectations and executed within budget and timescales.
- Work with internal and external clients, pitch designs, and understand client needs.
- Develop visual designs, and at other times, be responsible for recruiting and managing multidisciplinary third-party suppliers as well as internal design resources.
- Using best practice toolkit to implement new processes and practices to improve the efficiency of the design and creative department.
- Develop creative programs and design concepts that meet the business objectives of the organization and that advance our brand and proposition strategy
- Work with internal teams to generate ideas for pitching and proposals
- Work with other team members to deliver projects and activities to deliver against deadlines

Oct 2018 — Jun 2019

Lead UX Designer, Atlas Money

New York, USA

I led interaction strategies in sync with user goals and clients' business goals, developed navigation and structure

I lead a team of 4 designers:

- Designed wireframes and interactive prototypes
- Organized content, and tirelessly advocated for the needs and goals of real users.
- I made strategic and tactical UX decisions related to design and usability as well as features and functions.
- I created and assisted with information architecture and UX design for complex interactive projects.
- Defined digital strategies.
- Produced site maps, wireframes, prototypes and UX requirements documentation.

I also facilitated internal team communication, bridging the gap between visual design, functional development, and content. Communicated the value of these disciplines to clients. Grew to lead client engagements from a UX perspective.

I became the main contact for the client for all design deliverable, project managers depended on me to lead the design from kick-off meeting to final delivery, led the content workshop for the client, the client will reach out to me when it comes to anything design or speech science-related questions, I made sure all deliverable was done accordingly and participated in all internal and external meetings

Oct 2017 — Nov 2018

UX Designer, Hotels.ng

Lagos, Nigeria

Worked with an incredible team of designers and engineers, creating wire-frames, high-fi mock-ups, and prototypes to redesign the hotels.ng website to scale better and give it a more modern look.

At Hotels.ng I designed projects from inception to execution, working closely with research and content, as well as executives and stakeholders. It was quite a ride-touching product that affects thousands of users every day.

A large product I worked on was a completely redesigned experience around hospitality with Hotels.ng version 7, we went back to first principles, assessed usage, and streamlined the product to match top tier standards. I,

- Understood product specifications and user psychology
- Conducted concept and usability testing and gathered feedback
- Created personas through user research and data
- Defined the right interaction model and evaluated its success
- Developed wire-frames and prototypes around customer needs
- Found creative ways to solve UX problems (e.g. usability, find-ability)
- Worked with UI designers to implement attractive designs
- Communicated design ideas and prototypes to developers
- Kept abreast of competitor products and industry trends

Feb 2013 — Oct 2016

Visual Designer, Drake Media Concepts

Enugu, Nigeria

My goal was to translate marketing and branding strategies into innovative and impressive campaigns that stimulated target audiences. I,

- Generated clear ideas and concepts in tandem with the copywriter
- Produced sketches, storyboards roughs to visualize ideas
- Understood marketing initiatives, strategic positioning, and target audience
- Cooperated with the rest of the creative team across different types of media
- Took work from concept to final execution within deadlines
- Managed and delegated responsibilities to other designers and provided directions
- Presented completed ideas to clients/team members
- Stayed on top of all trends and maintained best practices

I was responsible for the visual style and images in magazines, newspapers, product packaging, and movie and television productions. I created the overall design feel for the company and directed others who developed artwork or layouts.

PROJECTS

Oct 2021 — Present

Eze Wholesale

San Francisco, USA

We are the world's first fully automated marketplace for trading electronics in wholesale quantities. Leverage real-time market data, secure payments, and automated shipping to safely expand your network and sell on Eze faster than anywhere else. I designed the Eze wholesale website and Admin Dashboard. Visit www.ezewholesale.com

Nov 2020 — Present

Carrot Credit

Delaware, USA

Carrot is a digital lending platform that gives you access to credit in United States Dollars, at low-interest rates. I designed the Carrot Credit website and the User dashboard.

Visit <u>www.carrotcredit.com</u>

COURSES

Jan 2021 — Feb 2021

Google UX Design Professional Certificate, Google

Sep 2020 — Dec 2020

How to Build Digital Products, Product School

Jun 2020 — Aug 2020

<u>Design Thinking and Global Startup, Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)</u>

EDUCATION

Aug 2013 — Oct 2017

Bachelor of Science (BSc.) Computer Science, University of Nigeria

Enugu, Nigeria

- Graduated with high honors
- Secretary-general, Nigeria Association of Computer Science Students (2015-2016)

Computer Science is unique because it provides a focus for the convergence of technologies. Its uniqueness naturally defines its role and dictates its increasing relevance in several disciplines and modern practices and techniques. The scope of application of computer science in the modern scientific and technological context is, therefore, infinitely wide.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Feb 2021 — Mar 2021

Lead Product Design - Ekobits ICT Academy

Lagos, Nigeria

EkoBits ICT Trust Foundation tackles poverty and creates work and economic growth by equipping teenagers and youths (who can't afford a university education and whose families earn less than 2 dollars daily) with global technology skills.

The youths advance on internet, graphic & web design, web development and film making. I volunteered to take on the product design cohort.

Aug 2019 — Oct 2020

Lead Product Design Mentor - CcHub

Lagos, Nigeria

Civil Society Organizations (CSOs) across West Africa are showing innovation by using technology to advance their work. Over the last two years, Co-creation Hub (CcHUB) has conducted security vulnerability assessments on twenty-eight civil society organizations across Nigeria and Ghana.

CcHUB discovered the current crop of technologists at CSOs across the two countries are not adequately equipped to tackle the technical needs of the advocacy space. This dearth of competent technologists in the advocacy space diminishes the desired impact of the work of CSOs

CcHUB is currently working to solve the aforementioned problem by aggregating both current technologists and aspiring public-interest technologists into a community of practice where they will receive training, peer support, network weave and leverage expertise to tackle critical technology issues as well as wider issues facing the civic space.

Feb 2019 — Jul 2019

UX Lead - Genesys Tech Hub

Enugu, Nigeria

Genesys Tech hub under Tenece professional services run a six-month internship program, For a period of 6 months, you'll learn how to build software products and businesses using a rich and well-structured curriculum. Understand the principles of designing user interfaces and experiences and learn to create user centered products. Learn and understand all the processes and resources required to transform an idea or product into a functioning and profitable business.

I volunteered to teach product design in the internship.

CAMPAIGNS

Nov 2021 — Mar 2022

Global

This was the second edition of the community campaign program, which was built and planned with the same structure and strategy as the first but better planned, defined, and executed following the lessons we learnt from the first edition.

I lead a team of 4 to execute this community campaign, the team was made up of a digital marketer, visual designer, and a digital marketer

Nov 2020 — Jan 2021

Enyata Build Up 1.0

Enyata Build Up 2.0

Global

The vision of this project is to provide learning resources/infrastructure and support 10,000 young Africans in their tech growth and journey over the next 5 years. The first edition which held in Q4 of 2020 was a huge success, 50 macbooks were given out to 50 young deserving tech talents in Nigeria with a 6-month subscription on Pluralsight to study any course of their choice.

We believe providing this resource will help empower a good number of Africans to build the next generation of digital platforms, helping to jointly make Nigeria and Africa the next technology hub of the world.

Key results at https://build.enyata.com/

INTERNSHIPS

Jul 2017 — Oct 2017

UI/UX Designer, Hotels.ng

Lagos, Nigeria

The Hotels.ng internship is a 3-month remote internship designed to f ind and develop the most talented software developers. Everyone is welcome to participate (there is no entrance exam). Anyone can log into the internship using their laptop. Each week, we give tasks. Those who complete them advance forward.

The intern coders and designers are introduced to complex programming frameworks and design tasks and get to work on real-world software. The finalists are connected to the best companies in the tech ecosystem and get full-time jobs and contracts immediately.

SKILLS Interpersonal

Interpersonal Communication

UX Design

Critical Thinking

Product Ownership

Interaction / UI Design

Prototyping

Management

Analytical Thinking

Building Relationships

Lean Startup

Visual Design

HOBBIES

Extreme Adventure

Blogging/Writing

Watching Documentaries

Photography

Team sports

REFERENCES

Valentine Oleka from Westwing, Germany.

valentinenwakibeya@gmail.com

Michael Okoh from The Peer, Nigeria.

ordrizzy@gmail.com

David Ukauwa from Grain, USA.

dukauwa.du@gmail.com

Namnso Ukpanah from Flutterwave, USA

namnsoukpanah@gmail.com

Friday Godswill from Alasco, Germany

faradayyg@gmail.com

Chimdindu Chimereze from CakeDefi, Singapore

creativechimdi@gmail.com